

Dr. Rebecca (Becky) SMETHURST



rebecca.smethurst @physics.ox.ac.uk



rebeccasmethurst.co.uk



0044 1865 273 640

Department of Astrophysics
Denys Wilkinson Building
Keble Road
Oxford
OX1 3RH
United Kingdom

I am a Junior Research Fellow (JRF) at Christ Church at the University of Oxford. My research focuses on the quenching of star formation in galaxies of different morphologies due to supermassive black holes. I am a member of both the SDSS-IV MaNGA and Galaxy Zoo teams. I am also an enthusiastic science communicator posting weekly videos on my YouTube channel, 'Dr. Becky', which has over 125,000 subscribers. I have also written a popular public science book entitled 'Space: 10 Things You Should Know' which was named one of Sky at Night magazines Top 20 books of

2019.

Research Experience

October 2018 -

Junior Research Fellow: Searching for Observational Evidence of AGN Feedback Christ Church, University of Oxford

January 2017 - September 2018

Ogden Trust Research Fellow: Galaxy Evolution: Inside-out or Outside-In? University of Nottingham

October 2013 - January 2017:

The influence of morphology, AGN and environment on the quenching histories of galaxies.

Supervisor: Chris Lintott University of Oxford

October 2011 - June 2012:

Searching for TP-AGB star signatures in post-starburst ('E+A') galaxies:

Supervisors: Russell J. Smith, John Lucey

Durham University

Achievements & Prizes

Caroline Herschel Lectureship Prize 2020
Royal Astronomical Society Group Prize 2019 - Galaxy Zoo Team
Vice Chancellor's Public Engagement with Research Award 2019 - 'Dr Becky'
Institute of Physics Early Career Physics Communicator Finalist, 2015
FameLab UK National Final 2014, Audience Winner & Judges Runner-up
Parent's Association Prize for Leadership, Bolton School Girls' Division, 2008
Prize for Achievement in Physics, Bolton School Girls' Division, 2008

Observing Experience

Observer at the Shane-3m at the Lick Observatory, California - May 2018
Remote observer with the Shane-3m at the Lick Observatory, California - October 2017
Observer at the CSO in Mauna Kea, Hawaii - February 2015
Remote observer, from Oxford, with the CSO in Mauna Kea, Hawaii - November 2014
Observer at the INT Spectrograph in La Palma, Canary Islands - May 2014

Conference Organisation

April 2019:

Lead organiser of SDSS-IV: MaNGA collaboration meeting, Oxford, UK

November 2017:

SOC member for .Astronomy 9, Cape Town, SA

July 2017:

SOC member of Galaxy Zoo Tenth Anniversary Conference, Oxford

June 2016

Head of SOC and LOC for .Astronomy 8, Oxford

Education

October 2013 - January 2017: DPhil, Pembroke College, University of Oxford Supervisor: Professor Chris Lintott

October 2008 - June 2012: MPhys, St. Aidan's College, University of Durham 1st class MPhys degree in Physics and Astronomy

September 1998 - August 2008: Bolton School Girls' Division A-Levels: Physics (A), Maths (A), Further Maths (A), Chemistry (A), General Studies (A)